MARINA SHALNEVA

CONTACT

52 Whyman Avenue, ME4 5TR, Chatham, Kent



(□) 07881536966



marina601@live.com

SKILLS

- · Problem Solving
- HTML5
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Risk analysis and Management
- Attention to Detail
- Policies and Procedures Implementation
- Performance Evaluations
- Financial Management and Reporting
- Superb Time Management Skills
- Cross-functional Communications
- Performance Improvement
- · Deadline-oriented
- · Great Verbal and Written Communication

CERTIFICATIONS

- Personal Alcohol License Holder
- Food Hygiene Level3
- Health and Safety level2
- First Aid Certificate
- Fire Marshal Certificate
- · Allergens training
- Complained Handling
- Managing Standards and Discipline
- Recruitment Selection

HOBBIES

I am very outgoing person who is passionate about sports and wellbeing. In my spare time I love to spend time outdoors.

Also, I have started a food blog:

https://italianfoodfast.com/

I am passionate about great food which you can make from scratch at home. In fact I have a basic understanding of:

I am a junior developer, currently enrolled in a Full Stack Software Development Diploma and actively pursuing an entry into the tech industry. I bring excellent background and professional exposure from hospitality, where I gained many transferable skills. Positive, ambitious and resourceful. Results-focused management professional offering over 12 years of progressive leadership experience. Transforms high-potential staff into outstanding leaders demonstrating creativity and savvy critical to financial and operational success.

EXPERIENCE

January 2016 to Current

General Manager Cote Brasserie, Dartford, Kent

- Operating high volume French Brasserie in Bluewater shopping centre with a team of 50 employees.
- Achieved consistent sales growth by 5% L4L 4 for years in the row.
- Have support 4 other restaurants within the area with Management development, marketing and business planning.
- In November 2018 have successfully directed an opening of a new site in Maidstone and spend 3 months building the business via marketing and building relationship with local community.
- Business planning and forecasting.
- Weekly financial reporting.
- Soft and hard KPIs are maintained.
- Monthly P&L reviews.
- · Marketing.
- Ensuring all the employees are compliant within food safety and health and safety standards.
- Recruitment.
- Ensuring the guest's expectations are exceeded and high level of customer service is always provided.
- Responsible for property maintenance.
- Staff training.
- Creating personal development plans for management team.
- Providing a full training to new managers hired for various locations.
- HR support within the area.
- Keeping a staff retention rate above 85%
- Developed effective business plans to align strategic decisions with long-term objectives.
- Designed modern employee recognition program which boosted productivity and improved morale.

October 2009 to January 2016

Senior General Manager Zipper and Villagio, Chatham, Kent

- Operate a multi-site and brand restaurant, 50's style dinner, Italian restaurant and American Italian bar and grill restaurant.
- Driven by the desire to succeed, took a well performing brands and increased net profit by 10%.
- Recruited to plan and direct the opening of 3 other site, managed all pre-opening recruitment activities and training.

- Social Media
- Marketing
- SEO
- · Google ranking
- Content Creation

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: English (fluent) Languages: Russian (native)

Driving License: Full UK driving license

Nationality: Italian

- Ensuring the KPI's are met within company standard, reviewed on the monthly basis.
- Driving teams to reach and exceed targets Local marketing Helping to oversee an area of 7 restaurant and report to MD
- Full financial accountability for all brands working to exceed budgets
- Customer satisfaction and retention focused
- Issuing financial reports on the weekly basis
- Full admin accountability for the area: HR, payroll, stock control, invoicing.

April 2008 to September 2008

Assistant Manager Simply Italian, Rochester, Kent

- Having started as a team member on the restaurant floor, I worked my way up to the position of Assistant Manager of this busy and vibrant Italian restaurant.
- My responsibilities vary from organizing the service in the absence of the manager, stock control and ordering, training new team members for our and other company branches.
- On rotation responsible for the end of the day cashing up and closing of the business.
- Planned team-building exercises to increase employee performance and job satisfaction.
- Monitored cash intake and deposit records, increasing accuracy and reducing discrepancies.
- Offered hands-on assistance to customers, assessing needs and maintaining current knowledge of consumer preferences.
- Generated repeat business through exceptional customer service and responded to customer concerns with friendly and knowledgeable service.

May 2007 to April 2008

Barista Pret A Manger, London, London

- I took part in all the areas of the shop front as well, such as stock control and maintenance of the bar through monitoring and engineer call outs.
- Responsible for training new team members to the company standards.
- I am very target motivated; during my training for Barista, I increased coffee sales in the shop by 2%.
- Restocked display cases with attractive arrangements to promote specialty food items like bagels and muffins.
- Learned every menu preparation and numerous off-label drinks to meet all customer needs.
- Maintained supply levels in counter and customer areas to meet typical demands.
- Provided in-depth information to customers on beverage preparation and offered samples of latest brews.
- Created original artwork for specials board display daily.
- Trained new team members with positive reinforcement and respectful, encouraging coaching.

EDUCATION

2021

Diploma in Full Stack Development IT / Programing Code Institute, Remote

- Continuing education in Code Institute and will graduate as a Full Stack Web Developer in July 2021
- Currently studying in the modern remote environment with Code

Institute and undergoing through my first project using HTML CSS.

- Using Slack platform to communicate with other students and mentors
- GitHub / Gitpod
- Bootstrap framework
- Attending seminars to undertake extra learning